Hello hi friends welcome to our channel
in this video we will talk about India's best
health insurance plans and their features
so that whatever you buy
covers your maximum health related expenses
I would like to tell you that neither
I am an agent nor I get
commission from any company I have done all the analysis
independently Friends
before moving ahead please subscribe to our channel friends
and ring the bell that
is visible on your screen so that
you get my latest videos first
Friends before choosing health insurance it
is important to understand about the near claim ratio
this tells how much percentage of the premium the company
gives back to the policy holders in claims this percentage should be
between 5290
for a good company
this ratio is published by IRDA which is the
regulatory body of the government I have
compiled here the
near claim ratio of top six health insurance companies of India in the
annual report of IRDA  From the report
published in December 2019, let's
look at the top six companies in India and
their claim ratios. The first is Apollo
Munich Health Insurance with a rate of
63%. The second is
Star Health and Allied Insurance with a rate of
63%. The third is Religare
Health Insurance with a rate of 55%. The third is
Max Bupa Health Insurance with a rate of 34%. The
fifth is
Aditya Birla Health Insurance with a rate of
59%. And the sixth is Cigna TTK Health Insurance with a
rate of 62%. Friends, all these companies
offer many different plans
for their different customers. In this video,
I have selected the best plans of the top three companies
and have explained in detail
their features. Along with this, they
also provide protection against coronavirus. The
first one is Apollo Munich
's Optima Restore. To play in the
friends, after the regulation of SDMC,
its name has become HDFC Ergo Health
Optima Restore. The second one  The first plan is Star
Health's Star Comprehensive. The third plan
is Religare's NCB Super Premium.
First, we start with the sum insured. The sum
insured decides
what your maximum limit will be at the time of claims.
In HDFC Ergo Health Optima Restore, it
starts from the free leg and the maximum
limit is up to the felt tip line. The
limit for Comprehensive is Rs 521 crore.
Religare NCP
Problem limit is Rs 275.
Flex Friends. All three policies
are available for individuals as well as family
plans. If you take a family plan,
this sum insured
is the combined amount of all the family members. The next
parameter is pre-hospitalization
expenses. In HDFC Ergo,
you get a cover of Rs 6000 for the hospital. You can cover all the
expenses before this, such as medical
tests and consultation fees.
In Star Comprehensive also, this
limit is 60 days and in Religare, this
limit is only Rs 1000.  30 days Now let's talk about
post hospitalization expenses. Here, the
SDM CR is 180 days in Star
Comprehensive, 9 days
in Religare and 60 days in Religare. HDFC Ergo
gives you the most accessibility in this matter.
Next, let's talk about no claim bonus. That is,
if you have taken a policy
and have not made any claim during the entire policy period,
then the company automatically
increases the sum insured at the time of renewing the policy next time. In HDFC Ergo
Health, you get a benefit of
fifty percent increase and this can go up
to one hundred percent. Let's understand this with an example.
Suppose you have taken a policy of Rs 5 lakh and have
not made any claim for one year, then the next
time your review will automatically be
7.5 percent. And if no claim is made for two years, then
your review will be
10 lines. And when you click this,
your accumulated benefits will be
decreased by 50%, that is,  If you
clean in the third year, then at the time of renewal in the 14th year,
your sum insured will decrease by 50% and
become Rs 1.5 lakh. Friends, the
same rule applies to Comprehensive as well, and there is
no change. Religare NCB Super
Premium has slightly
higher benefits. Your sum insured increases by 60%
in every claim premium, and this
can increase the maximum by 1.5 times. If
you clean, your no-
claim bonus will be reduced by 60%.
Friends, here the base sum insured,
which we took in the example of FiberLike, does
not change. Any
increase or decrease occurs,
changes are made on the bonus. Now let's talk about the next
perimeter, Restore Benefit, which is a very
important parameter. No matter which
company's policy you take, be sure to keep this in
mind. Restoration benefit is the best
in HDFC Ergo Health because here
you get 100% protection.  Restoration is available
in case of a full claim.
For example, if you have a phablet policy
and you claim for two lakhs, then
five lakhs will automatically be
added to your sum insured and you
can claim again. There is a
restore benefit in comprehensive and according to
recent changes, you
can also claim in comprehensive, but here your
summary is stored only after your existing cover is carefully
consolidated. Suppose
you have a sum assured of Rs 5 lakh and your total
claim is Rs 5 lakh, then you will
get only Rs 5 lakh for the first claim or the five lakhs will be added
again to your policy for the next claim.
Restoration benefit is not available in Religare without any extra premium
and the rest of the terms are similar to Star Comprehensive. The
next parameter is the waiting period.
In HDFC Ergo and Star Comprehensive, the waiting period is three years, in Religare it is four years,
but this Star
Comprehensive offers this option.  You can avail buy back, which
means you
can reduce your waiting period by paying extra premium. Now let's talk about the
minimum age, about all three points. The
minimum age is 90 months for any
child to be added to the family floater plan
and the maximum age to
join is sixty-five years in HDFC Ergo,
sixty-five years in Star Comprehensive
and there is no app in Religare. Now let's
talk about room rent. There is no app
for single and private AC room in all three policies. There is a
front neck
parameter. Day treatment.
Daycare treatment is covered in all three policies.
Now let's talk about eye and dental care.
This is not covered in SD Senior Health.
Its limit is more than ₹250 in Four Comprehensive
and it is next to ₹125 in Religare.
Outpatient or consultation charges are
not covered in HDFC Ergo. The
limit is ₹300 in Star Comprehensive and
this is not covered in Religare also. Now let's talk  Regarding
maternity cover, HDFC Ergo
Help does not offer maternity cover. Star
Comprehensive offers a limited amount cover
after three years, while Religare offers this
cover only in the Better Than Fifty Shades
policy. Now let's talk about Ambulance
Star, which offers AC and CO Health, with
hospitalization at ₹2,000. Star
Comprehensive also offers hospitalization at ₹2,000 for a total policy
year. Religare also offers hospitalization at ₹2,000. The
next parameter is
preventive health checkup. HDFC Ergo
Health
offers this option above five lines, but it is
available only if you abstain from any surgery for two years.
Star Comprehensive offers this option only
in Every Client
Premier and Religare also have the same
policy. Now let's talk about treatment at
home or domiciliary treatment. All three
policies cover this, but there are some terms and
conditions. Now let's talk about the Balance
Program. This is available in both HDFC Ergo Health and
Star Comprehensive.  There is an
awareness program in which you join
and do the given activities from time to time,
then you get a discount at the time of renewal
which can be up to 810 percent
but there is no such option in Religare Super Premium. Let's move
ahead and
see some exclusions
in all the three policies. On genital diseases i.e. diseases
before birth,
diseases caused by misuse of drugs and alcohol, sexually transmitted diseases,
mental disorders are usually not covered
and in all the three policies the cover
starts thirty days after the policy
except accident. The next parameter is
alternative disease i.e. Ayurveda AYUSH, so
this is not covered in HDFC Ergo.
In Star Comprehensive and Religare
you can claim up to a limited amount.
Friends, the last parameter of our video
is hospital coverage. This is very
important and it is important for you to see which
hospitals near you are
covered in which policies. All over
India, if you look, it is difficult to see.  It is
for cashless treatment with Mode and 1000 hospitals and this number is 98100 for
Star Comprehensive and 7000 for Religare
and if we talk about premium then for example
I have calculated the
premium of a thirty year old male here
who is not a West Indies and has
not taken a family floater, has kept the sum insured as
duplex, so in this case
your premium in ASSI Argos will be 804, in Comprehensive
820 and in NCP Super Premium 7208, you
can calculate your premium yourself according to your conditions by going to the website,
so friends I would recommend you that
before choosing a policy, you should evaluate your conditions
and the stage of your life at this time and
see what options you get in the policy, then after that
take a decision which policy you want to choose,
you must write in the comments of this video
which policy you have chosen and
why so that maximum people can take
advantage of this.  Friends, I hope
you liked this video.
Please like and subscribe and
also share it with your friends and family.